curriculum vitae of

LAURENT BRUSA

address Tegner Str. 2 Berlin 10439 Deutschland

email laurentbrusa@me.com SO stackoverflow.com/multitudes portfolio github.com/multitudes/portfolio url https://multitudes.github.io LinkedIn laurentbrusa cell +49 1522 9623248

Profile

Between 2022 and 2023 I worked as sole iOS developer at rooom. My responsibilities among others included the communication with Apple through Apple Store Connect, testing and upload apps to TestFlight, creating apps from design storyboards, adding AR and VR features and updating legacy code.

I now recently started freelancing but I am open to new job offers.

In January 2020 I finished my two years-long "Umschulung" for Software Developer in Berlin and got certified by the IHK, the German Chamber Of Commerce. As part of the certification's curriculum, I did a 6 months internship for iOS programming, where I developed a museums iOS app for iPad as my exam project. For the exam, I wrote the documentation and held a 15 min presentation in German.

My specialisation is in programming for iOS, with the UIKit or SwiftUI frameworks using the Swift programming language.

Originally I passed my A-Levels in Electronics and Math with full marks and after working in the electronic components testing industry I went back to the university. Later in London, I worked in the Apple Travel EMEIA team as a travel consultant providing travel solutions for Apple corporate and retail operations; I collaborated on organising and ticketing travel and accommodation for various events such as the iPhone's and iPad's launch.

Experience

iOS Developer. Freelance. April 2022 - present

rooom, Löbstedter Str. 47a, 07749 Jena. February 2021 - April 2022. iOS Developer.

Aerticket, Boppstraße 10, 10967 Berlin October 2016 - September 2017 Chambers Travel, Am Borsigturm 27, 13507 Berlin July 2015 - September 2016 Corporate travel management for different accounts such as GoPro, Epson, Fossil

APPLE Travel, 1 Hanover Street, W1S 1YZ London January 2012 - May 2014 Senior Business Travel Consultant in the BCD travel implant in the Apple HQ

CWT, Global House 424 Bath Rd, UB7 0EB Greater London 2008 - 2011 Senior Business Travel Consultant

ANA, Hythe House 200 Shepherds Bush Rd, W6 7NY London 2007-2008 Air France Marines Dept, Brent House, HA9 1BF Wembley 2002-2007 Airline Reservation and ticketing

Education

IHK Software Developer Certificate at Cimdata, January 2018 - January 2020 Training in Tokyo at ANA headquarters and at Haneda Airport. 2008 Japanese Language Proficiency Test 3 at SOAS University. 2007 Ticketing and fares training by Air France. 2005 "Frei" University, Berlin. Theatre Studies, Music and History of Art. 1995-1998 Humboldt University, Berlin (D). Translator and interpret courses in German. 1993 VIII Technical College, Turin, Italy. Bachelor's Degree in Electronics. 1989

Languages

Fluent in spoken and written French, Italian, German and English.

Skills

Swift and iOS app development, C, full stack with React. Python for Machine and Deep Learning. Networks and system administration.